I sometimes ask myself
if I could go back in time in a time
machine, say maybe five
or six years,
and I could look at myself today,
would I see myself sat next to
products like this and say, "James,
you are a fucking sellout"?
Oh no,
can't monetize the video because I said
the word "fuck." We'll be all right.
Two things I want to get into.
First of all, being a sellout, and two,
why I
actually had to apologize to Chris
Williamson.
One of the things
that people hate me the most on social
media is someone called a
grifter.
And when asked what a grifter actually is,
it is someone that
doesn't use the very thing
that they promote or sell.
And although I have problems with a lot of
products that Chris Williamson is
involved with, like AG1,
he annoyingly still drinks it every single
day.
So therefore,
I do not have the ability to call him a
grifter.
Then when we come to the word "sellout,"
me personally, I think you're a sellout
if you promote other people's shit for
money. If someone goes, "Oh,
here's $10,000.
Talk about the moisturizer
that you don't use," and you're there,
"Oh yeah, this
moisturizer's done amazing things for me,"
then you're a piece of shit.
And to this day,
I've never done a paid post.
Up until recently,
I had the virtue of being able to say to
people, every
penny I've made has come through education
because I have the fitness training
app, I do the talks,
I've written the books.
But this year or last year,
that changed with the arrival of Nootonic,
and some of
the comments on social media have gone
pretty shit, quite bitter, and people are
saying,
"You're a sellout." So to answer the
question of if I could go back in
time, would I consider myself a sellout?
The answer is I don't know.
But the last video I did got the crypto
bros very angry when I was trying to say
that I didn't think that crypto
was a great form of investment.
And I said to people,
"I think it's very important
that you maybe look to invest in
something like building an audience,"
which doesn't have to be massive.
You don't have to have millions of
followers to do well in life.
For most of you,
if you could have 100 clients,
you'd be laughing.
And with a 1% follow rate,
that means you only need 10,000 followers.
You might have to check my maths on that.
It's not my strong point.
But the thing I want to back up is this.
Content creation for me,
and hopefully you,
is such a powerful tool because we get
to manipulate the market.
So whereas some of you crypto bros may get
online and
go, "Oh my god, XRP's gone up. Buy XRP.
Sell Solana.
Bitcoin to the moon.
Diamond hands," whatever it is,
your influence on that is
quite difficult unless you just convert
other people to buy
and invest in the coin.
I don't know. Then for those of you
that invest into ETFs and the S&P 500,
which I
personally think are great,
you kind of just have to sit back
and it's, "How's your
investment?" "Oh yeah,
I'm just going to wait 30 years
and hopefully it'll be
good." Bringing a product to the market
similar to a piece of content means that I
can influence the market because
if you think of my share portfolio as my
social media account,
with every piece of content I put forward,
I'm
hopefully positively influencing
that share price.
And that share price
is how close someone
is to potentially doing business with me,
whether they need a workout plan from my
app, whether they buy my book next time
they're in an airport.
But then there's volatility to this
market.
I have had takes that have not been great.
For instance, in the pandemic.
When the vaccine came out, a lot of the
research that I was looking into gave me
the stance of being pro-vaccine.
I changed that over the years
that came afterwards,
but with the evidence in front
of me, and I took a big L. And
that definitely had a negative impact on
my
popularity or share price
or whatever because I had a bad take.
So although you can positively impact
things, you can also have a bad one.
Your market cap crashing to zero
is something like getting canceled,
because that's
really what the fear of canceling is.
It's taking your reputation
and throwing it to the ground.
The reason some people think I've sold out
is they think this isn't mine. This is.
So I don't get paid to promote this.
In fact,
I've never had a penny from the company.
I've invested hundreds of thousands of
pounds into the production of that,
and any of the money
and profit we make goes into producing
more.
So then we can do deals with retail,
and we can get it into different places.
Trust me, four years ago,
I never thought I'd write a book.
Two years ago,
I never thought I'd own a drink
which has done several million
dollars in sales, so thank you very much.
But like I said,
I've not had a penny of
that because we're expanding it.
So what am I saying? For me,
and hopefully for you,
maybe right now it's very
difficult to think of yourself having a
product because I never thought I would
have one.
But through doing what I did to make my PT
business flourish, which was
grow on social media, make good content,
grow an email list, other opportunities
arise, such as the book deals.
That came through at 300,000 followers,
maybe 600,000 followers,
and maybe a million followers.
And I got the highest accolade on all
three of those books, and it was probably
only through proving to people
that I could get people enough to trust me
to buy a
book that there was the confidence to
start a project like starting your own
drink.
And again,
this was tarnished by Logan Paul
and KSI relaunching Prime,
which probably didn't put them into the
best PR circle of all time.
Anyway,
the reason this product excites me
is because it is something that is
influenceable. Again,
many investments that we have,
you just kind of
have to sit back and hope
that things go in a good direction.
Whereas with this, with every video,
with every piece of content that I make,
I can
make an impact on someone to potentially
try it and buy it.
And I know that the product
is good enough that when they do try it,
a large
percentage of them
are going to become recurring customers.
The truth is that my mom
and dad have a mortgage on their property
which is quite
significant.
And if I do the maths on how much money I
make from my own ventures,
my books or whatever,
my ability to have the liquid capital cash
to pay off their
mortgage before they want to downsize
is finite.
And a project like this excites me because
if we can grow this big enough, someone
will come along and buy it.
No one's going to buy my fitness app
because that app
doesn't exist without me marketing it.
No one's going to come along
and buy the rights to my books because
they need me to
write it. But the truth is that
if I can grow this to a $20, 30,
50, or $100 million business,
which we're on the way to,
someone could come along,
take 50% of the business,
and I'm in a position to pay off all the
mortgages of all
the people around me. And if
that means I have to get a little bit of
bad press, so
be it.
And I've seen in the comments people
calling me a sellout, and it's kind of
novel because no one's ever said
that for all the years
that I've done social
media, but for me,
it's a conscious decision.
And ultimately,
I think the majority of people
that see this product and see what
it is, they get it. They get
that you would diversify it into other
markets.
They would appreciate that nootropics
are still misunderstood.
Most people don't even know they're
supplements for the brain
that can help you
concentrate for longer.
And this product hasn't even been released
yet But I'll
tell you more about that
when we release it.
I've said this many times,
and hopefully this could be a little pep
talk that you
can take with you. There
is a really fine line between hating
someone, being
jealous of them,
and thinking they're a cock,
and actually being inspired by what
they do. Case in point, Adam Sullivan.
We can overlay a few pictures of him
probably standing in front of his
Lamborghinis. He's a personal trainer,
and he actually arrived to the market
after
me and has probably done better than me.
And for a small while, I was resentful,
and I blocked him because I just didn't
want to feel the way I felt
when I saw him,
and now we're really good friends.
And I've mentioned him in content before
because I'm saying I'm not infallible to
the advice that I give. In fact,
I'm a hypocrite in many of the things
that I say.
But I'm much happier now
that I'm motivated by him rather than
being bitter about
it. And for some of you, maybe
if your knee-jerk reaction to me promoting
Nutonic was that I'd sold out,
maybe it could excite you a little bit
because I'm
just a very ordinary bloke.
I've got four A to C GCSEs,
which in English means I only got four
grades that were worthy enough.
You need five to go to college.
Two of those are science,
one of them's French, and
the other one's PE.
I had a very ordinary life up until the
age of 27 when I had my
first selfie. I never had any real money,
or I'd never been called
impressive at anything I'd ever done in my
life.
I was pretty average playing rugby as
well.
And it was only at 30 going to 35
that I actually started to produce
something good
out of my life. So sitting here,
and I'm going to flex, I have at least
four, depends how you look at them,
seven-figure businesses.
I'm either the luckiest bloke alive,
or I finally cracked the code in my
mid-30s.
And like I said, when it began, I
was a PT using social media, just
hoping that I wouldn't have to walk the
floor to get clients.
Then social media kind of took off,
and I was like, "Wow,
I can post videos and get
clients that come through." Then I
was like, "Wow, Harper Collins
are paying me
hundreds of thousands of pounds to write
books." Wow, I'm now creating events off
the back of books. Wow,
I've now done so much within my own
business that I
can leverage launching a brand to seven
figures in six months.
Wow,
and now that I've done so much within my
own business as, let
me put this straight,
a fucking idiot that's just spoken to
camera for 10 years,
that I'm now in a position to help small
businesses grow their business and brand
on social media. So to those of you
that thought I've sold out, fuck you.
And to those of you that think,
"Good on you, mate.
I wouldn't mind doing something like
that for myself," I wish you the best of
luck,
and I'm going to turn up on this fucking
channel every time I can to try and help
mold and motivate you to do the things you
need to do.
Because ultimately, I'm not even
that great of a business coach. I'm not.
And in my mentorship,
sometimes someone makes a shit video,
and I say, "That's
shit." I tell them what to do.
They then post another one,
and guess what?
That one's pretty shit, too. But I say,
"Hey, bro.
I'm so happy you turned up again today
because you could have taken the bad
feedback I gave you yesterday
and cried like a little bitch,
but instead you turned
back up and made another one,
and I'm proud of you for that."
And sometimes in
life, all you need
is a big brother like me to say, "Huh,
pull your fucking head
out your ass and do
that again better."
And that's probably why that business is
doing so well as well.
If you haven't tried the product,
you should.
Not because it's great or whatever,
because there's two outcomes to the
reality of
this situation.
Either I'm a fucking sellout piece of
shit, or
this is actually really good
and I've kind of stumbled across gold.
And the only way you're going to find out
is to try it.
So I'll leave the normal links for the
mentorship in the description, but also
leave the links for Nutonic.
If you're in the UK and USA,
you can get the drinks.
Australia, don't want to get into it.
TGA won't let us import it.
Other story altogether. And then
when you try it, come back to this video,
and you
can either comment going, "It
was actually pretty good,"
or you can say that I was
full of shit.
And if you've really got your knickers in
a twist, pop me a fucking
email,
and I'll send you the money back for the
other 11 cans. Good day.
Hmm.
It's caffeine, right? Oh,
YouTube probably put a video up there they
recommend you
watch, so you should probably watch
that as well. Bye-bye.